Andrew James

Senior engineer | London, UK

Contact



ajames.dev



contact@ajames.dev



phunkren



Andrew James

Education

BSc (Hons) 2.1

Audio Technology & Multimedia Glasgow Caledonian University 2010 - 2014

Graduate

Frontend Nanodegree Udacity 2016

Expertise

HTML

CSS/SCSS

JAVASCRIPT

RFACT

Profile

My passion for digital technology continually drives me to advance my skill set as a software engineer. With an analytical mindset and strong communication and frontend development skills, I thrive in environments where I can learn from others and inspire those around me.

Over the years I've refined a set of technical principles to strive towards, namely: complexity should only be introduced when it's unavoidable; code should be easy to reason with and delete; avoid abstracting too early, and the top priority is always the best possible user experience.

Experience

Senior engineer

BCG Digital Ventures
April 2019 - Present

As a senior engineer I collaborate with design, UX, growth, and product cohorts to engineer a robust and well documented product that can be successfully taken to market by a startup business. It is also my responsibility to support lead and mentor associate engineers wherever possible.

Notable work

Beema

Frontend engineer

Fathom

June 2017 - March 2019

Interests

GATSBYJS

GRAPHQL

CSS-IN-JS

Hobbies

CYCLING

GUITAR

VIDEO GAMES

RUGBY

References

Written references available on request.

Working at Fathom allowed me to work alongside a number of highly-skilled professionals on a range of challenging fintech projects. The majority of my time was spent working with React, with additional exposure to React Native, GatsbyJS and Angular 2.

Notable work

- Anaplan
- Access Fintech
- Commerzbank

Associate engineer

Cohaesus

Feb 2015 - June 2017

Cohaesus is a commerical advertising agency where I learned the fundamentals of frontend web development. During my time with them I worked both in-house and offsite at some of London's top advertising agencies, on both green field and legacy codebases.

Notable work

- Highland Park
- Fat Face
- WWF

QA tester

Rockstar North

May 2014 - Feb 2015

Credited as a QA Tester on Grand Theft Auto V, I was responsible for finding, reproducing, and accurately reporting issues in detailed bug reports. It also involved providing clear and concise critical analysis and feedback of reported issues and executing functionality, regression, and user acceptance testing across various platforms.